that is actually an old program series from the 90s
There the actors at the City Theater of Gothenburg
come in after the Saturday rehearsals and
told stories or read poems on different themes.
We invited Gothenburg's freelance actors for this
And we have been running for three semesters now.
And today we have Timo Nieminen and
Annika Nordin here and the theme are prospects.
Yes right now we have to keep away from each other.
For it is hard to hug you have to keep more than one
arm's length.
Prospects yes ..
In the synonym dictionary we find words like:
panoramic,
hope,
hopes,
Views.
And from views
the associations can easily go to windows.
Windows, it is a strong theme of many artists through the ages.
Charles Baudelaire highlighted in one of his prosepoem:
There is nothing deeper,
Secret
From Baudelaire to Saarikoski, Pentti Saarikoski.
One dark gray morning I go to buy wine.
The only one in the small bus and in the big one, out of three.
Until a day when the little one is no longer needed
It replaces the big one and we, we have become a winery
And the great bus drivers drive the small and the small bus drivers chop our firewood.
Desolate to be the only bus's only
and embarrassing that in the big product one of three looking down at the knee
A dark gray morning in February.
New thoughts are not needed for a long time
On the high bridge I doubt its strength
In the cafe I sit and look at the high villas opposite
where there lives people who are happy,
in its way
Other people who turned the wind so that the spirit of the city
not breathe against them
Sunny mornings and
the sailboat's mood in the strait
null
a sober grogg with summer evening on the other side
promises made them
null
The sign is read
Everything is forbidden
The pond is turned off
Shameful water lilies do their best
submit
melancholy
And dream
in defense
Harry Martinson
Suddenly the whole pamped lay for my soul
with raising horizons, roaming horns
horses, sheep and fleeing ostriches and gazelles
And butterflies
In millions.
Gauchon rolling his horse over winding rivers
damp flowering virgin soil
brown moors along glittering ocean
Vidalita
null